Howard Moorepark Correspondence
Howard Moorepark Correspondence
1910-1964
Moorepark, Howard.
0.25 linear ft.
American literary agent. Collection consists of correspondence with various authors, artists and literary figures, including authors H. T. W. Bousfield, Anna Mary Wells, Ivor Bulmer, Israel Cohen, Malachy Gerard Carroll, Christoffel Lessing, and Frederic Dannay (aka Ellery Queen); poet Earle Birney; and artists John Steuart Curry and Edward Hopper.
3175646
Biographical History
Howard Moorepark (dates unknown) was an American literary agent. His clients included crime novelist Ed Lacy (Leonard S. Zinberg) and poet William Stafford.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Howard Moorepark Correspondence consists of correspondence with various authors and other literary figures. Correspondents of particular interest include authors H. T. W. Bousfield, Anna Mary Wells, Ivor Bulmer, Israel Cohen, Malachy Gerard Carroll, Christoffel Lessing, Frederic Dannay (aka Ellery Queen); poet Earle Birney; and artists John Steuart Curry and Edward Hopper.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by correspondent.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Moorepark, Howard.; Literary agents -- United States.; Correspondence.; Literary agents.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unspecified, circa 1964.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Family or personal, 1909; 1912,; 1921 (Box 1)
  - Allsop, Kenneth, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Ashley, Robert P., 1952-1953 (Box 1)
  - Birney, Earle, 1957-1960 (Box 1)
  - Bousfield, H.T.W., 1947-1949 (Box 1)
  - Bradbury, Bianca, undated (Box 1)
  - Carroll, Malachy Gerard, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Clark, Laurence, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Israel, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Curry, John Steuart, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Dannay, Frederic (aka Ellery Queen), 1959 (Box 1)
  - Fraenkel, Heinrich, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Gawsworth. John, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Gooden, Stephen, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Graham, Stephen, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Grant, Joan, 1959-1962 (Box 1)
  - Heintzelman, Arthur W., 1934 (Box 1)
  - Hopper, Edward, 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - Jacobs, W.W., 1910[?] (Box 1)
  - Kinney, Troy, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Lessing, Christoffel, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
  - Lucioni, Luigi, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Macbeth-Raeburn, Henry, 1932 (Box 1)
  - MacKaye, Percy, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Mackenzie, Compton, 1962 (Box 1)
  - MacNab, Ian, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Matthieson, John G., undated (Box 1)
  - Morse, A.R., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Neblett, William H., 1953 (Box 1)
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Pearson, R.H., 1959; 1961 (Box 1)
  - Philips, C.E. Lucas, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Pick, J.B., 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Sherlock, John, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Short, Frank, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Sullivan, Edward J., 1928 (Box 1)
  - Thomas, Ivor, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Tomlin, Frederick (E.W.F.), 1959-1961 (Box 1)
  - Turngren, Annette, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Wells, Anna Mary, 1950; 1955 (Box 1)
  - Werth, Alexander, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Woodman, Dorothy, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Woodward, W.E., 1924; 1928 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, A-Z (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified or illegible, includes one unidentified photograph of three men (Box 1)